Umar Hifzhulhaq Sulaiman

Bogor, Indonesia | Email: <u>umarhifzulhaq96@gmail.com</u> Linkedin: <u>www.linkedin.com/in/umar-hifzhulhaq-sulaiman</u>

Website: https://umar-hs.github.io/

SUMMARY

Data-oriented psychology undergraduate with hands-on experience taking part in several psychological research projects. With experience in developing psychological measures and background in quantitative analysis utilizing RStudio, SPSS and Microsoft Excel, keen on learning further quantitative analysis techniques. Familiar with basic psychological theories, interested in experimental psychology, psychometry, and meta-science.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Data Analyst — Political Psychology Laboratory University of Indonesia

December 2023 - Present

- Responsible for data management, cleaning, analysis, and visualization in several projects handled by laboratory
- With Professor Mirra Noor Milla, analyzed inmates psychological data and reported the result for National Counter Terrorism Agency (BNPT)
- Taken part in development of inmates psychological measures for BNPT

Assessment Psychometric Intern — Rakamin Academy

September 2023 - December 2023 (Intern)

- Analyzed psychometric properties of several psychological scales. Conducted EFA/CFA analysis using JASP and IRT analysis using IRTPro.
- Conducted data cleaning in Google Sheet, utilized and developed various custom formulas and scripts to streamline the process.

Research Assistant — University of Indonesia Research Grant Project

December 2022 - Present (Part-time)

- Responsible for assisting research project headed by Laras Sekarasih Ph.D
- Conducted literature review on parental mediation
- Prepared psychological instrument for the study: reviewing relevant instruments, translating, and inputting instruments to survey platform
- Cleaned and managed data from across three countries and prepared digest reports used by the team
- Conducted analysis using structural equation model

Learning Operator — Websis

December 2022 - March 2023 (Intern)

- Responsible for implementing Websis's training and development programs
- Organized program schedules in Google Calendar
- Acted as facilitator for a bootcamp: responsible for preparing and delivering materials, reviewing participant activities, and managing participants
- Managed and organized data from an audit program conducted by Websis in spreadsheet

Content Writer/Contributor— Faxtor Indonesia

October 2022 - Present (Freelance)

- Completed thorough research into assigned topics.
- Completed interview with relevant parties regarding assigned topics
- Prepared essays and Instagram content about psychology mainly relating to psychometry for

Student Researcher — Faxtor Indonesia

May 2022 - July 2022

EDUCATION

University of Indonesia — *Psychology (Undergraduate)*

September 2019 - August 2023 (Expected)

- **GPA**: 3.93
- Completed several psychological research coursework with excellent score
- Conducted experimental social psychological research on leadership for graduation thesis. Prepared survey platform used by 218 participants.

ORGANIZATIONAL EXPERIENCE

Department vice head — Departemen Pengembangan Psikologi Islam (P2I) FUSI Psikologi UI 23

February 2021 - December 2021

 Responsible for preparing and implementing the department's annual work programs, work programs include organizing discussions, making infographics related to psychology.

Tutor Metodologi Penelitian & Statistika Deskriptif — KLIMAKS 2020

September 2020 - December 2020

• Hold tutoring sessions to participants on the topic of Research Methodology & Descriptive Statistics.

SKILLS

- Data Wrangling with Excel, google sheet, & R (tidyverse)
- Psychological Data Analysis with R (psych, lavaan)
- Data visualization with ggplot

AWARD

Best Undergraduate Thesis — Faculty of Psychology University of Indonesia July 2023